# SAI TEJA IRRINKI

**J** +91 9493322788

## Senior DevOps Engineer

🔽 <u>saitejairrinki91@gmail.com</u>



**G** www.softwarelife.in

• medium.softwarelife.in

github.softwarelife.in

in linkedin.softwarelife.in

### ■ PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

This is SAITEJA IRRINKI working at **Zelarsoft** as a Senior DevOps Engineer. Having experience in Infrastructure Provisioning, Configuration Management, Version Control, Code Quality, Environment Administration, Defect-Tracking, Release-Management, Continuous-Integration, Continuous-Delivery, Cloud Computing, Container Orchestration, and Scripting for Automation, Static Web Development, and Operating Systems - Linux, Windows.

## ☐ TECHNICAL SKILLS

- © Operating Systems Linux, Windows
- © Cloud Platforms AWS, AZURE, GCP Basics
- © Containerization Tools Docker, Kubernetes
- Virtualization Vagrant, Virtual Box, VMware ESXi
- Automation Shell Scripting, Ansible, PowerShell
- Infrastructure Provisioning Cloud Formation, Terraform
- © Version Control Tool GIT, Azure Repo
- ® Build Software Maven
- @ CICD Jenkins, Azure DevOps
- Web/App Server Tomcat, Apache HTTP Server
- ® Static Web Development MkDocs
- Agile Project Management Azure Boards

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

- Experience in IT area comprising configuration management, Deploy, CI/CD pipeline, Cloud, and DevOps methodologies.
- **♣** Expertise in troubleshooting the problems generated while building and deploying.
- Working Experience on **Git**, **GitHub**, and **Jenkins**. Debugging issues if there is any failure in broken Jenkins build and maintaining Jenkins build pipeline.
- ♣ Working Experience in Azure Cloud and Azure DevOps
- Proficient in developing Continuous Integration / Continuous Delivery pipelines.
- Experience with containerization tools like Docker.
- Experience on build tools and packaging the source code using Maven.
- ♣ Scheduled builds overnight to support development needs using **Jenkins**, **Git**, and **Maven**.
- Experience in integrating Unit Tests and Code Quality Analysis Tools like **SonarQube/Cloud**.
- Experience in using Nexus Repository Manager and Azure Artifacts for Storing Artifacts.
- Experience in orchestration tools like Kubernetes using KOPS, Kubeadm, K3S, Minikube, etc.
- **♣** Experience with AWS services IAM, Compute Engine, Kubernetes Engine, and Storage Buckets.
- ♣ Experience with Amazon Web services Creating, configuring, and Managing EC2, Storage, IAM, S3, VPC, ELB, Cloud Watch, EFS, Route53, Elastic Cache, Amazon MQ, and Other services.
- Experience in using Apache Tomcat servers for deployments.
- Performed continuous Build and Deployments to multiple DEV, QA, Pre-PROD, and PROD Environments.
- **♣** Working Experience in Shell Scripting, PowerShell, AWS Cloud Formation & Ansible.
- Expertise in Static- Web-Documentation using MkDocs.
- Ability to learn new skills quickly.

# **EDUCATION**

- ♣ B Tech Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2020
- ♣ Intermediate MPC 2016
- ♣ 10<sup>th</sup> class SSC 2014

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- ♣ Working as DevOps Engineer with Zelarsoft Pvt Ltd from March 2022 to till date.
- Worked as DevOps Engineer with Visualpath Pvt Ltd from March 2021 to February 2022.
- Worked at Visualpath from Nov 2020 to Feb 2021 as an Intern in DevOps Background.

# PROJECT-1

Name: Celito Drug Design Platform (CDDP)

Client: Celito Tech

Tools: Azure Cloud Services, Azure DevOps, PowerShell, Power Apps, Windows OS.

### **Roles and Responsibilities:**

Worked with team to Develop Application Requirements.

- Created a Workflow & Branching Strategy with the Requirements.
- ♣ Setup/managed Azure Repos and Branching Strategy.
- **★** Established a Build/Release pipeline with automated build and Continuous-Integration.
- ♣ Automated the provisioning of Powerapps Environments (Dev, Staging, Pre-Prod, Prod) using Azure DevOps Tasks and Azure resources (App Registration, Blob, Back-up Center, Cosmos DB, Key Vault, Azure VMs) using PowerShell and Templates.
- ♣ Monitored Automated build & Continuous-Integration process to drive Build/Release Failure Resolution.
- Automated and Implemented system backup and recovery procedures.
- ♣ Worked with Software Development and Testing-Team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability, and performance.
- Documented project design for reference and future use cases
- ♣ Involved in CI/CD process and integrated SonarQube with Azure DevOps for Quality-Analysis.
- ♣ Have hands-on experience in writing PowerShell when needed to automate jobs and tasks in the pipeline.
- Experience deploying infrastructure resources utilizing ARM templates.
- Automated Release Notes Generation from Azure Boards and PR's.
- Implemented high availability with Azure classic and Azure Resource Manager (ARM) deployment models.
- Experience delivering applications in Azure.
- ♣ Ability to Document deployment processes and transfer knowledge to other operational team members.
- Ensure all cloud deployments follow established workflows.
- Supports Development and production systems and deployments.

## PROJECT-2

Name: Techbricks Edu

Client: Internal

Tools: AWS, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, SonarQube, Git, GitHub, Maven, Nexus, Linux.

### **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- ♣ Involved in CI/CD process and integrated GIT, Nexus, SonarQube, and Maven Artifacts build with Jenkins
- Creating and maintaining namespaces, config maps, secrets, and Services in Kubernetes
- ♣ Experience in working on AWS and its services like IAM, VPC, EC2, EBS, S3, ELB, Auto
  Scaling, Route 53, Cloud Front, Cloud Watch, EFS, and Others.
- ♣ Experienced in Cloud automation using AWS Cloud Formation templates to create customized VPC, subnets, NAT, EC2 instances, ELB, and Security groups.
- ♣ Experienced in creating complex IAM policies, Roles, and user management for delegated access within AWS.
- Identify, troubleshoot and resolve issues related to the build and deploy process.
- For Securable purposes store the Docker images in the Docker registry.

# LY DEVOPS ENGINEER ROLES

#### Cloud Migration using Lift and Shift Strategy on AWS Services using

- ♣ VPC, Ec2, S3, Application Load Balancer, Route53
- IAM to give secure access to AWS account using MFA.
- Tightly controlled Security Group for firewall rules of EC2
- EBS volume for storage on Ec2, Snapshot for Backups of EBS
- Auto scaling for Automatic scaling of Ec2 instance based on CPU usage

#### Modernization on AWS Cloud Services used

- Beanstalk for PAAS for Tomcat Web App
- RDS for MySQL Database
- Object storage S3 to store and retrieve files

- Route53 for Private and Public Hosted zones/Records
- Amazon MQ for fully managed RabbitMQ,
- ElastiCache for the in-memory data stored in the cloud
- Monitoring with Cloud watch, Grafana

#### Continuous Delivery of Java Web Application

- CICD Pipeline using Jenkins, Git, Maven, Nexus and SonarQube
- Deploying Artifact to Beanstalk from Jenkins
- Jenkins Pipeline As A Code for CICD

### Configuration Management using Ansible

- ♣ Ansible AdHoc commands to execute remote tasks
- Ansible playbook for Service/Server Deployments
- ♣ Ansible Roles for modular and reusable automation framework

#### **Docker Containers**

- Building customized Docker images using Dockerfile.
- Docker-compose to run MultiContainer Docker Application.

### Infrastructure Provisioning Using

- Ansible
- Cloud formation
- Terraform

#### Kubernetes

- Creating Production grade K8s cluster using Kops & Kubeadm.
- Hosting Containerized Application on K8s cluster
- Pod, Service, Replication Controller, Deployment, Secrets, Replicaset.

### Azure Cloud & Azure DevOps

- ♣ Automated the provisioning of Azure resources (App Registration, Blob, Back-up Center, Cosmos DB, Key Vault, Azure VMs), Manual Tasks and Release Notes using PowerShell and Templates.
- Created a Build/Release pipeline with automated build and Continuous-Integration using Azure DevOps.
- Integrated Teams/Outlook with Azure Pipelines for Build Result/PR Notifications.

### **E** DECLARATION

I hereby affirm that, to the best of my knowledge, the information provided above is accurate.

Place: Hyderabad IRRINKI SAITEJA (IS)